[
    {
        "question": "The common currency of European Union is ...............",
        "options": [
            "Dollars",
            "Euro",
            "Pound"        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "Trade that takes place between different regions within the same country is knows as ............... trade.",
        "options": [
            "Domestic",
            "International",
            "Foreign",
            "Bilateral"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "Information technology helps to carry out ...............",
        "options": [
            "Online-transaction",
            "Online-shopping",
            "Online-trading",
            "Online-banking"
        ],
        "answer": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "Good ............... promotes business.",
        "options": [
            "Communication",
            "Transport",
            "Marketing",
            "Administration"
        ],
        "answer": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "Each region has different ............... conditions.",
        "options": [
            "Geographical",
            "Political",
            "Regional",
            "Dismiss"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "A region supplies commodities to other regions when is has produce in ..............",
        "options": [
            "Large",
            "Excess",
            "Less",
            "Same"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "Identify the type of trade ............... Tata steel sells to European countries.",
        "options": [
            "Internal",
            "International",
            "Regional",
            "Domestic"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "Trade is an important ............... activity.",
        "options": [
            "Political",
            "Social",
            "Economic",
            "Cultural"
        ],
        "answer": 3 
    },
    {
        "question": "OPEC controls the international trade of ..............",
        "options": [
            "War weapons",
            "Crude oil",
            "Uranium",
            "Technology"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "Balanced balance of trade means exports and imports values are .............",
        "options": [
            "More",
            "Less",
            "Same",
            "Uneven"
        ],
        "answer": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "The headquarter of world trade organisation is in ..............",
        "options": [
            "Paris",
            "Geneva",
            "Singapore",
            "Madrid"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "SAARC helps to remove unrest in ...............",
        "options": [
            "South asia",
            "North asia",
            "Europe",
            "Africa"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "The ............... of the commodity is determined by its quality.",
        "options": [
            "Size",
            "Price",
            "Grade",
            "Value"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "India imports spare parts of machinery from European countries known as ............... trade.",
        "options": [
            "Domestic",
            "International",
            "Regional",
            "Internal"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "............. Court protects consumer's rights",
        "options": [
            "District",
            "High",
            "Session",
            "Consumer"
        ],
        "answer": 4
    },
    {
        "question": "Size of the country diversity distribution and availability of natural resources affect ............... trade in the country",
        "options": [
            "International",
            "Internal",
            "Global",
            "Foreign"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "Trade between India and Japan is called ...............trade.",
        "options": [
            "Domestic",
            "Internal",
            "Bilateral",
            "Global"
        ],
        "answer": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "............. traders buy goods on large scale from the industrialists or farmers.",
        "options": [
            "Retail",
            "Wholesale",
            "Companies",
            "Individuals"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "Unfavourable balance of trade is when import is ............... then export.",
        "options": [
            "More",
            "Less",
            "Where",
            "Same"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "Grain were ............... in lieu of work done in barter system.",
        "options": [
            "Exchanged",
            "Bargain",
            "Sold",
            "Supplied"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    }
]